Let's talk about the quality management
plan then.
Just like any management plan,
any of the management plan, the quality
management plan is
one of the subsidiary plans
that make up the project management plan.
So remember just as a
review, the project management
plan is made up of
subsidiary management plans.
It's made up of the baselines.
It's made up of some of the additional
components.
So in this case then, we're talking about
the subsidiary management plans,
which are, again, all of the management
plan, such as scope management plan,
requirements management plan, cost
management plan, etc.
One of those is this one here,
the quality management plan.
And just like any management plan, is
documenting procedures, is documenting how.
How are we going to plan,
manage, monitor, and control
quality management process
throughout the project?
So it's documenting the quality management
procedures for the project, and it's going
to include procedures for both,
quality control and quality assurance.
So remember, quality is not just testing
the product.
That's just one part.
Quality is built into the entire project
process.
It's making sure all procedures are being
followed.
So the quality management plan then is
going to be documenting how the policies,
procedures and guidelines will be
implemented to achieve the quality
objective of the project is
going to be describing the
quality standards and
objectives that's going to be used.
So, ISO standards,
6-Sigma standards, or, you
know, whatever standard
is going to be used, right?
And how we're going to implement those
standards, right?
How are we going to, how do we know that
we're actually going to be following those
standards, building codes and so on and so
forth?
So it's describing the procedures for
that.
Right.
So also roles and responsibilities.
Who's going to be responsible?
What teams are going to be responsible for
testing the product?
the process?
Making sure that all of our
procedures and all of our
product as well is in line
with the appropriate standards.
So who is responsible for all of that?
That's also going to be documented here as
well in the quality management plan.
Remember again, quality control and
quality assurance.
Whenever we're coming up with quality,
the quality management plan is going to
include procedures for both, testing the
product, as well as testing the process.
Also things like quality management tools.
What quality management tools are we going
to be using?
And we're going to be covering some of the
quality management
tools in subsequent videos.
But one of those tools could be a quality
audit.
So how often are we going to be going to
be performing an audit, right?
And who's going to be responsible for the
audit?
And so and so forth.
So again, all of these
procedures are going to be
documented here in the
quality management plan.
Then also including
things like, for example,
non-conformance, what
happens if we identify issues, right?
What happens if we have defects?
How do we handle that situation?
What's the procedures then for fixing
defects?
What's the procedures
for if we've identified
any corrective actions
that need to be done?
Machines broken down, how do we handle
that situation?
Or a process is not working correctly.
How do we handle that situation?
Plus also things like continuous
improvement.
So what are the procedures for continuous
improvement?
Somebody's identified that something needs
to be improved.
then what are the procedures to implement
those improvements?
So again, any non-conforming item is also
going to be, or how we're going to deal
with any non-conforming
item, is going to be
documented here in the
quality management plan.
So whether it refers to a corrective
action or a defect.
And then plus, obviously, preventive
action.
I mean, how are we going to build quality
into the product?
How are we going to build quality into the
project, into the process.
Again, all about following appropriate
standards.
What standards are we going to be
following?
And how are we going to be following those
standards?
So we're also going to be putting some
quality metrics procedures in place as well.
We're going to be putting some quality
metrics to determine how successful our
quality management process is,
to determine the success of our quality
implementation, such as, for example,
percentage of tasks, complete.
How many tasks have been completed over
time?
Compared to how many we're expecting to be
complete over time.
Number of defects over time.
The number of defects per week,
or the number of defects per month,
are they going down over time?
Even the total downtime per period.
Down time of machines, for example.
Have the, so the downtime of machines per
month?
Are they within tolerance limit?
Also things like cost performance index.
CPI, we're going to cover cost
performance index in a separate
video, which is covered in
the cost management section.
But again, these are all certain metrics
that you might put in place.
Now, what I just mentioned
was just obviously
just a couple of them, just a handful.
But every organization, every industry are
going to come up with their own metrics to
determine how well or how successful the
quality.
implementation is for this particular
project.